

OLIVIA CHAPMAN UI/UX Pesigner

Profile

- UX/UI Designer with an array of creatiivity and design experience.
- Background in Ecommerce, customer service and photography.
- Proven track record of producing UX and UI projects from research to high-fidelity prototypes.
- Blends outstanding problem solving skills with user centered design solutions.

Contact

931.334.6401

olivialchapmanui.@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/olivialchapman/

Portfolio

https://www.behance.net/ oliviachapman16



Developed a Music Native iOS App by conducting user research, creating user flows, and designing prototypes. Beginning with low-fidelity wireframes to high-fidelity wireframes using Adobe XD.

<u>View ToonIn</u>: https://tinyurl.com/44jsk8cr

Designed a Mood Tracker Native iOS App by conducting user research, competitive analysis, and designing protoypes. Beginning with low-fidelity wireframes to high-fidelity wireframes for both iOS and Android. **View Moodie:** https://tinyurl.com/bdhahc3j

Created a Jewelry Store Native iOS App by performing detailed investigation and making iterations based on user preferences. Created user personas, wireframes and user testing.

<u>View Bling:</u> https://tinyurl.com/mrxp54a2

Experience

2016 - Present

Freelance Photographer/Graphic Designer

Spring Hill, Tennessee

Works independently, using cameras to capture people, events, nature and objects. Creates elegant solutions to complex design problems. Design and deliver creative solutions for various industries.

2018 - 2019

Painter/Ring Engraver

Groove Life / Spring Hill, Tennessee

Responsible for painting the engraved portion of the silicone rings. Attention to detail and color accuracy is of the utmost importance.

2019 - 2020

E-Commerce Associate

Groove Life / Spring Hill, Tennessee

Responsible for processing customer order information, utilizing Shopify. Prepare orders for shipment and communicate out of stock issues with fulfillment lead. Work with operations and warehouse staff facilitating and resolving warehouse system issues as they relate to the Ecommerce software platform functions.

Education

2020 - 2021

UI/UX Design Specialization

Career Foundry

A year long intensive course for UI/UX Designers specializing in UX fundamentals, methodology, and research driven approaches to design.

2020 - 2021

Front End Development For Designers

Career Foundry

Learned essential coding skills to be among a few designers in the industry who can speak the developer's language. Deliver elegant solutions to real problems by crafting functional, responsive code.

Skills

Adobe Creative Cloud | Adobe After Effects | Adobe XD | Balsamiq Case Studies | Competitive Analysis | Figma | InVision Graphic Design Principles | Journey Maps | Mockups | Rapid Prototyping Sketch | Usability Testing | User Interviews | User Research